Ahmed Ragheb

ragheb.ahmed@outlook.com +31 618277153 – Utrecht, Netherlands 13/05/1990

https://linkedin.com/in/ahmed-ragheb

Software Engineer

Highly autonomous, initiative-taking engineer who strives for a good balance between code quality and delivering business value. Has been involved in various kinds of web systems from CMS, CRM, IT Health Care, News Portals and Educational management platforms, drives seamless project turnarounds under strict deadlines and budgets, solves complex technical challenges and issues.

TECHNICAL STRENGTHS

- +9 years of hands-on knowledge and experience as a Software Engineer mainly with .Net (Core) and C#.
- Hands-on experience with AWS and Azure cloud services.
- Hands-on experience with multiple database engines (SQL, Postgres, DynamoDb).
- Hands-on experience with NodeJS.
- Good experience with Front-end technologies (Angular, TypeScript, HTML5, Jest).
- Good Experience with E2E Testing (Selenium, Protractor).

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

04/2017 - Now | Snappet | Full Stack Software Developer

- Architected, implemented and deployed a high available API for serving content to pupils app and teachers dashboard with SLA 99.99% (30M requests per day).
 - Tools: .Net Core, EF Core, AWS ECS, CloudFront, AWS DMS, AWS WAF, SQS/SNS, RDS Aurora.
- Architected, implemented and deployed a Secure Content Storage Service based on signed cookies to protect all the static content in the content domain.
 - Tools: NodeJS, CloudFront, AWS KMS, AWS Lambda, API Gateway
- Member of DevOps team that responsible for maintaining Snappet infrastructure and put the guidelines for other teams regarding deploy, monitor and alerting their services.

08/2016 – 03/2017 | Schouten en Nelissen | Application Consultant

- Implemented and deployed a Coaching tool to enable SN clients to register for new courses.
- Refactored and maintained of SN Research tool.

04/2015 – 07/2016 | Sarmady – a Vodafone Company | Software Developer

- Implemented the new version of <u>Fil-Goal</u> (one of the biggest sports sites in the Middle East).
- Implemented and maintained <u>Egypt Independent</u> Newspaper (one of the biggest newspapers in Egypt).
- Integrated and implemented with Coca-Cola Egypt to lunch a website for a game competition.

11/2012 - 03/2015 | DrBridge | Software Developer

- Implemented <u>Vezeeta</u>, a free service in middle east that allows patients to find specialized doctors and book the appointment online.
- Implemented <u>DrBridge Clinic</u>, an e-prescription for doctors to Treat and diagnose their patients.
- Piloted and integrated with scan labs to show patient results in his/her medical history.

02/2012 - 11/2012 | Dewan-Soft | Solution Developer

• Implemented multiple small applications to small business (retailers, sports clubs ..).

02/2011 - 06/2011 | Link-DEV | Intern Solution Developer

EDUCATION

• BSc Computer Science, Faculty of Computer Science, Helwan University. (2007 – 2011). GPA: 3.33.